Muhammad Saqlain Arif

Islāmābād, Pakistan



saglain.sial05@gmail.com



03336740548



linkedin.com/in/msaqlainarif

Summary

Full Stack Engineer | PHP | Vue.js | Nuxt Js | React Js | Laravel | Elastic Stack | Wordpress | GraphQL | AWS | Frontend Dev | Docker | DevOps

Over 9+ years of successful experience conceiving software architectures, designing and implementing multitier applications and system integration solution. Very good understanding of application analysis and design concepts. Strong ability to apply optimal design patterns to the system design and employ extreme programming techniques to the robust implementations.

Experience

(PTA Software Engineer

Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA)

Jun 2020 - Present (2 years 9 months)

- Responsible for maintaining and improving an existing software application with a huge userbase and database.
- Building new applications to give insights into the client's data and ensure that the business decisions are data-driven.
- Maintaining and improving an existing software application with a huge userbase and database.
- Working on ICT Indicator database to collect data from Telecom Operators which helps Pakistan Ranking in ITU.

Skills: Laravel, PHP, Web API, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Core, C#, Web Api, Sql Server & MySql

· PostgreSQL · Angular Js, Keycloak, Docker, AWS, Authentication & Authorization, Microsoft Identity Server, ELK, Custom cron background job.

Sr. Executive CRM Solutions

Ufone 4G

Nov 2018 - May 2020 (1 year 7 months)

- Ufone CRM solution customization & maintenance
- Service based architecture and Oracle as back-end DB.
- Business Process Re-engineering, Office Automation, E-Filing, Extensive UML modeling, Requirement Engineering, System Architecture and Design
- Application development .Net framework , Laravel, PHP , Web API, Angular Js, Bootstrap 4, SQL Server
- CI/CD

ADB Software Consultant

Asian Development Bank (ADB)

Aug 2018 - Jan 2019 (6 months)

Work parallel with M&E specialist and created online tool for NDMRF for project monitoring and evaluation.

Tools and Technologies:

Laravel, PHP, Bootstrap, Vue js, Mysql

(PTA ICT & Software Consultant

Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA)

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018 (1 year)

Development of ITU - Telecom Indicators Database (PTA Admin & Telecom Operators)

PTA Ligation Portal features enhancement & maintenance

PTA Financial Application

Tools & Technologies:

C#, ASP.NET MVC, Microservices, Angular 1.6.7, SQL Server, Web Forms, Oracle

Software Engineer

COMSATS Internet Services

Feb 2016 - Jun 2017 (1 year 5 months)

- Capable of understanding and contributing to the technical solution from design through to code level, produce accurate delivery estimates and manage the transition from analysis through to design and delivery.
- -Provide regular and effective progress updates to general manager.
- Work closely with relevant teams internally to ensure alignment and coordination across operations as part of the seamless implementation of existing and new systems.
- Contributing to post implementation reviews helping to demonstrate success or otherwise of projects.

Skills: Bootstrap, Jquery, HTML, CSS, Codeignitor, PHP, Wordpress

🚄 Web Developer

Syslab Technologies Sdn Bhd

Jun 2014 - Jan 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Lead a project for the parking management system, which is used to assign parking slots and management of invoice and online payments.

Mobile apps backend development.

Skills: Web API, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Push Notification, Codeignitor, Laravel, PHP, Mysql, Wordpress



Software Developer

Creative Vision International

Mar 2013 - May 2014 (1 year 3 months)

Web apps and websites development and i was working junior web developer.

I worked on web based tools and technologies.

Skills: PHP, Zend, Wordpress, Joomla, Jquery, Javascript, Css, html

Education

Abasyn University Islamabad Campus

MSCS, Computer Science 2015 - 2019

Federal Urdu University of Arts, Science & Technology, Islamabad.

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Software Engineering 2009 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

Web Application Development - EVS

Issued Jul 2011 - Expires Dec 2011 5641/m-11

Skills

Laravel • PHP • Agile Application Development • Vue.js • RESTful WebServices • React.js • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • MySQL • Full-Stack Development • WordPress

Honors & Awards

WOWZAPP 2012 Hackathon for Windows8 - Microsoft

Dec 2012